

## **Moustafa Mahmoud Ahmed Mohamed**

# **Assistant IT Manager**

Email: mustafa.mahmoud99988@outlook.com

Portfolio: https://mustafa99988.github.io/Portfolio/

Mobile: (+971) 543239190 Dubai, United Arab Emirates

# Summary:

A highly motivated and committed System Administrator with 6 years of experience in supporting colleagues by analyzing and resolving technical issues with effective solutions. Proactive and collaborative, with a demonstrated track record of strategic thinking and taking initiative to meet deadlines. Acknowledged by both management and peers as someone who embraces challenges and new responsibilities, ensuring tasks are completed accurately.

## **Personal Data:**

- Place of Birth: Asyut, Egypt.
- Nationality: Egyptian.
- Driving License: UAE Driving License (Dubai).

#### **Education:**

Bachelor Degree of Commerce – Asyut University (2013 – 2017).

# **Language Literacy:**

- Arabic: Mother Tongue.
- English: Very Good Speaking, understanding and writing.

#### **Certificates:**

- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Not Certified.
- Microsoft Certified System Administrator (MSCA) Not Certified.
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900) Certified.
- Microsoft Azure Administrator Associate (AZ-104) Certified.

## IT Systems Knowledge:

## **Operating Systems:**

- Microsoft
- Installing, Configuring, and Administering Windows 2012 / 2016 / 2019 Server.
- Implementing and Administering Azure Infrastructure (laaS PaaS).
- Installing, Configuring, and Administering Hyper-V Vmware vSphere Azure VMs.
- Installing, Configuring, and Administering Domain Servers.
- Installing, Configuring, and Administering Win 7 / 10 / 11.

- Linux & macOS
- Good experience in managing macOS & fair experience with Linux OS.

## Skills:

# **Personal Skills**

- Ability to work on a variety of complicated problems of moderate scope and complexity where analysis
  of data and/or situations requires evaluation of multiple factors.
- · Fast Learner as well as strong decision-making skills.
- Excellent communication skills, both in English and Arabic.
- Initiating planning and executing property IT projects.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Opera PMS (v5.5 and 5.6).
- Micros Workstation 5A & 6 with Simphony POS System, Enterprise Management Console (EMC) and Online Reporting and Analytics.
- Door Lock Systems and Keycard (CISA, Inhova, VisionLine, Vingcard).
- · Payroll and HR System (HITS Naspro, Solution and Oasys).
- Accounting System (iScala, Hyperion, Smartview, DMS, EPSearch and Birchstreet).
- Call Accounting and Minibar systems (TigerTMS and Hotlync).
- Backup Systems (Symantic, IronMountain onsite & offsite).
- Restaurant Reservations Systems (Viya App and ServMe).
- Spa Booking System/Sales Assistant (TAC).
- Printing Servers (SafeQ).
- Electronic Registration Cards SAMSOTECH eReg Solution.
- Ticketing System (ServiceNow).
- Active Directory (AD) and Group Policy (GPO).
- Microsoft Azure.
- SCCM / MECM.
- Microsoft Intune.
- Microsoft Dynamics 365.
- · Microsoft Office 365.

## **Work Experience:**

### Assistant IT Manager – Hyatt Regency Dubai - (April 2023 – Current)

- Perform a daily inspection of the server hardware condition and implement necessary measures to address the hardware problems.
- Monitor the server's backup status daily and resolve any problems encountered during the backup process.
- Confirm that there is a sufficient stock of all items and equipment to keep the hotel functioning during
  equipment failures or malfunctions.
- Assisting other departments in maximizing the effectiveness of the hotel's systems.
- Aligning IT infrastructure with current and future business requirements and goals.
- Evaluating risk, developing network recovery and backup processes.

## Assistant IT Manager - Park Regency Sharm El Sheikh - (Nov 2020 – April 2023)

- · Conduct daily checks on the backup system to make sure all IT data is complete and error-free.
- Monitor the capacity of shared drives and the data stored within, and then report the status to the IT Manager.

- Address any user-reported requests or issues, resolving them directly or coordinating with the system vendor for support.
- Deliver exceptional service to the hotel guest.
- Demonstrated excellence in managing requests from companies like The New York Times, Amazon, and the American Chamber of Commerce for equipment setup and installation during COP27.
- Assist in the inventory management and ongoing maintenance of hotel operating equipment.
- Advice IT manager about any system upgrade or new technology that improve the work environment and employee's productivity while extracting work out of the system.
- Maintaining contacts with other departments regarding the storing of critical and important data.
- Participate in meetings and online conferences in the absence of the IT Manager.
- Help employees understand hotel systems and provide training on IT policies and security awareness.

## Information Systems Coordinator at Hyatt Regency Sharm El Sheikh - (May 2019 – Nov 2020)

- Support hotel staff & guest with technical issues and setup conference meeting for hotel management.
- Installing and configuration computers and other devices (printers, photocopiers, laptops, micros workstations, kitchen printers and other devices related to the hotel operation).
- Performing site vulnerabilities remediation according to Hyatt cyber security team guidelines and recommendations.
- Resolve tickets and incidents assigned by the global IT operation team.
- Check the user security groups, email accounts, shared email groups and system access to ensure the right privilege for every user according to their job title.
- Prepare the quarterly user rights reports for systems as requested.
- Check for any issues on the systems and servers including software and hardware issues and report it to the IT Manager.

#### Night Auditor at Gardenia Plaza Hotel & Resort Sharm El Sheikh - (June 2017 – Dec 2017)

- Review all the income revenue and trace it and check if there some documents are missing or if there something wrong with the documents.
- Worked as front office cashier to settle the guest extra charges.

# **Projects:**

- Guest network infrastructure upgrade:
  - Cabling (Fiber & UTP)
  - Installation and configuration of new Access Point Controllers.
  - Installation and configuration of new Switches.
  - Installation and configuration of the Gateway.
- ➤ In-place upgrade of servers from Windows Server 2012 to Windows Server 2019.
- Implementation of new host servers and storage:
  - Procurement of new servers and storage.
  - Installation and configuration of both the new servers and storage.
  - Live migration of Virtual Machines from the old servers to the new server with zero downtime.
  - Setting up the cluster failover functionality to ensure the systems' high availability.
- Samsotech eReg Solution (Electronic Registration Card)
  - Coordinate with the relevant vendors and strategize the implementation (Samsotech, Oracle)
  - The preparation and configuration of both (Database server & Application server).
  - Installation and configuration of iPads at the reception desks.

#### References:

Abdelhalim Ezzat – Director of Finance Park Regency Sharm El Sheikh.

Ahmed Talaat – IT Manager Park Regency Sharm El Sheikh.

Jocelyn Ong – Director of Finance Hyatt Regency Dubai.

Amr Khalil – IT Manager Hyatt Regency Dubai.